[School 2021]
[Kim Yo Han]
[Jo Yi Hyun]
[Choo Young Woo]
[Hwang Boreumbyeol]
[Kim Kang MIn / Jeong Seok Ho / Seo Hee Sun]
[School 2021]
Ready!
Start!
[Gong Ki Joon]
[Nulji]
I fell.
I got back up.
But I lost my way.
Gong Ki Joon.
♫ Dream on. dream on ♫
♫ Dream on ♫
[School 2021]
[Episode 1: What do I do now?]
[This is an unreasonable dismissal]
No more unreasonable and unfair dismissals!
We want to keep learning from Kim Moo Kyung!
Did you see the reason for upright Mr. Moo Kyung's dismissal?
It is absurd.
[Unreasonable dismissal!]
This is an unreasonable dismissal!
No more unreasonable and unfair dismissals!
What?
I heard it would rain.
Mind your own business.
Seriously.
Yeah!
Hey. you. How cool are you going to make that jump?
Why?
Seo Young is watching.
I know.
- Let's go. let's go.
- Easy. easy.
♫ Dream on. dream on ♫
♫ Dream on ♫
S***.
What's he doing?
Look at that.
Get up.
Is it really okay not to say goodbye to the kids?
Last goodbye? That's so cheesy.
When you leave. just go coolly.
Aigoo. Mr. Kim Moo Kyung. you're still here.
Oh. yes.
Good work. Be well.
Yes. you too.
Ms. Song Chae Rin. where are you going?
The meeting starts soon.
I'm okay. Just stay.
I'll just see him off to his car.
What about the meeting?
I'll be right back.
Geez...
Why do you insist on seeing me off?
Do you think I'll get lost?
Even adults can lose their way.
Hang in there. Ms. Hong.
Holding on is winning.
There isn't much time left until Cheol Joo's next trial. right?
I'll keep working on Cheol Joo's trial.
Just focus on the kids here. Ms. Chae Rin.
And especially the ones who'll go out on site.
The kids loved the woodworking class.
What will they do now?
There'll be another good teacher.
I think they already interviewed someone.
- They're quick on things like this.
- I know.
Gosh. Why is it raining so much?
No more unreasonable and unfair dismissals!
We want to keep learning from Mr. Kim Moo Kyung!
No more unreasonable...
Mr. Kim.
You really don't listen to me until the end.
Mr. Kim. are you really leaving like this?
No way.
I'll fight until the end.
Hey. Fight if you want. but you have to be in class.
You should stop her as her homeroom teacher.
Who can stop Ji Won?
You said you'll be the best carpenter in our country.
Where do you have time to be doing this?
Aigoo.
Here.
Bribe.
It's what I used when I won the National Championship.
If you become famous one day.
you have to tell them you're my student.
Mr. Kim.
Come now.
Fighting.
Get to class.
Go inside.
[Moo Kyung]
We can go home now...
Is the treatment on your injured ankle going well?
Yes. It's much better.
Right. Don't overwork yourself.
You know that even if you don't train. you have to do rehab. right?
Yes.
Carpentry?
Is your life in the new department going well?
Yes.
Alright. cheer up.
Here he comes.
Didn't he fall earlier?
Due to my ankle injury.
I quit taekwondo that I did for 11 years since elementary school.
But the coach and I both knew my ankle was already better.
We don't have much time left. Manage your weight.
- I just...
- Yes. sir.
didn't have enough talent.
Start the warm-up.
One. two. three. four. five. six...
Where am I supposed to go now?
What's this?
Seriously.
[Anniversary of Gyeong Min's death D-1]
Anyway. Jin Ji Won. you're amazing.
You were the last one standing.
Sorry. we couldn't be with you until the end.
It's okay.
You'll both be blacklisted by the school.
Only you would look out for us.
That's right.
- Oh!
- What? Why?
- I'm hungry.
- You are?
Should we go to the snack store?
A puppy lives inside my stomach...
- A puppy lives in her stomach.
- It rumbles...
Where are you going?
Hey. Gong Ki Joon.
Home.
Looks like you're skipping school.
You told me to lay off.
What's up with him?
♫ Not knowing makes me want to know more ♫
♫ Liking you sometimes makes me more anxious ♫
♫ I want to see the glimmering sea ♫
[Cha Gyeong Min]
♫ On my way there. I miss you more ♫
♫ Another day passes by ♫
How are you?
I quit taekwondo.
♫ I think of you ♫
Hey.
What do I do now?
♫ And then. in one moment ♫
♫ The heart that aches ♫
I miss you.
♫ Will you. will you remember me? ♫
♫ Me. a child who looked at you ♫
♫ who looked at you ♫
♫ I think of you ♫
♫ That's love ♫
♫ And then. suddenly I feel that way again ♫
I'll be going now.
♫ Without knowing. I want to know your heart ♫
♫ My heart has grown overnight ♫
♫ I want to see the sparkling night sky ♫
♫ I miss you more on these strange roads ♫
Grandpa.
Oh. welcome.
What are you doing here? You have back pain.
Yeah...
You're using this space again?
I'm trying to clean things up in advance.
Why suddenly?
Was the house auctioned off?
Yeah.
The bids fell through for so long. It was about time it succeeded.
Just leave it. I'll do it.
Alright.
I'll earn a lot of money and buy this house back for you.
I should live long to see my grandson become rich.
It won't take that long.
I have a lot of time.
And I need money.
Anyway. there were a lot of trials and errors in the beginning.
It really couldn't be helped.
So the important thing is that
I realized. 'I'm becoming a professional in my field.'
That thought made me feel really proud.
At the center was the Nulji High School architectural design department and the apprenticeship class.
I'm utilizing a lot that I learned at school in the field now.
That's all I have to say today. Not sure if it was helpful.
Now. ask away any questions you have.
Yes?
So. did you become employed full-time right after you took the apprenticeship class and graduated?
Yes.
For me. I signed a contract with the company in 11th grade.
I worked and studied at the same time.
and got hired full-time before graduating. and I'm still working there.
Yes?
Wouldn't it still be better to work after going to college?
Did you regret it or anything?
I'm not sure.
Rather than going to college without any thought.
wouldn't it be more efficient to work at a company
and go when you think you need to?
You all know P-TECH. right?
Yes. we know.
P-TECH?
I'm using that to take college classes on the weekends.
Of course. there is no College Scholastic Ability Test or tuition.
Yes?
But it's hard enough for us to earn our certificates now.
Isn't apprenticeship too much?
Right. working an apprenticeship can be more work than just a regular curriculum.
But think about it.
You're going on-site to learn while still attending school
and you get a monthly salary deposited every month to your bank accounts.
Huh? Isn't this really appealing?
You won't start your 20s with a debt.
You'll start it with savings.
Yes?
How much is the monthly salary?
Monthly salary...
Every company is different.
But I guarantee you it's more than the minimum wage.
Including the four national insurances.
Yes?
So...
what's an apprenticeship?
Huh?
Hey.
Be quiet.
Why?
Just be quiet.
Alright. no more questions?
That's about it for the talk with your sunbae.
They're recruiting one more apprentice
at Sang Rim Housing. where Jung Min works.
- so if anyone's interested-
- Me.
I get to go on-site. right?
I want to do it.
Oh. you.
Ji Won. Yes.
Alright. Anyone else?
Me too.
You too?
Why-oh. okay.
Okay.
What are you doing?
Put your hand down.
Hey. Gong Ki Joon.
Why are you interested in an apprenticeship?
You don't even know what it is.
Why?
Am I not allowed?
No. but...
You never even took the major classes properly while doing taekwondo.
They said they'd teach me.
You're doing this on purpose. right?
What are you talking about?
- Wow.
- Whoa.
- I say yes.
- I bet 500 won that they used to date.
That can't be right.
The whole class saw Jin Ji Won beating up Gong Ki Joon in fourth grade.
Ki Joon got a double nosebleed. It was a whole mess.
Hey. that was then.
Why would Ki Joon suddenly apply to the apprenticeship?
Because he wanted to work with Ji Won?
No. I applied to earn money.
Yes.
Even in elementary school. there was a rumor they were dating.
Please focus on my skills. not those rumors.
I dreamed of becoming a carpenter since elementary school
and it hasn't changed at all.
They were supposed to select one.
This isn't romance. It's a 'screw-you.'
I did it for the money. not my dream.
I'm prepared to endure.
Ho Sung. do you know anything?
You were close with them since elementary school.
Ki Joon and Ji Won. are they enemies or lovers?
It's hard to tell.
Gosh...
What's going on? You guys were badmouthing me. huh?
Yeah. Hold on a second.
Seriously.
How did the apprenticeship with Sang Rim go?
Huh?
- They're both good.
- Yes.
Well. you only have to meet the bare minimum for the major grades.
For now. you should both prepare to interview with Sang Rim.
Ki Joon. all you did was sports. huh?
How about we just go with Ji Won?
Stop talking about that!
- I'm hungry. Hungry!
- Hear me out!
Come on!
I'm hungry!
- When is Min Seo coming?
- I think that's her.
Oh. there's Min Seo!
- Min Seo!
- Hey. Min Seo!
Look who got off work on time?
Of course. You guys were desperately calling me.
Hello.
- He's there!
- Hurry!
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
[Byeol's Diner]
- Hello.
- Hey. guys.
Long time no see.
Hurry. go in.
Long time no see. oppa.
Yeah.
I'm a bad son.
Aigoo. So you know.
Jjolmyeon for all four of you?
Yes!
Aigoo. aigoo. I'm full. Aigoo...
It took me super long. even after getting into apprenticeship. to do OJT.
I know.
They said we could go right on-site. so I shot my hand up.
Wow.
But that's unexpected that Ki Joon applied for an apprenticeship at our company.
Yeah...
Hey. You didn't secretly want Ki Joon in that spot instead of me. right?
Gosh. Of course not.
Of course. I would love it if you could be by my side.
Hey. anyway. didn't they say the new woodworking teacher would be coming tomorrow?
Whoever it is. they won't be like Mr. Kim.
Yeah.
I hope he has Mr. Kim's personality and good looks on top of that.
Aren't you wishing for too much?
What? It wouldn't hurt for him to be good-looking.
We would see him every day.
Ta-da!
- This is on the house.
- Thank you!
- Eat up.
- Thank you for the food!
I'll call you unni from now on!
[Byeol's Diner]
Aigoo.
Gosh. I haven't worn dress shoes in a while. Hurts like hell.
Aigoo...
So hot.
Gosh...
Geez...
Excuse me. do you have a light?
Thank you.
I quit smoking six months ago.
But if I do this. it makes me feel like I'm smoking. and it calms me down.
It's my first day of work. so I'm a bit nervous.
Do you know Nulji High School over there?
Oh. you're not from around here.
That's where they gathered kids who gave up on studying because this doesn't work well.
Shouldn't you go to the hospital?
You're bleeding.
Mind your own business.
Oh. okay.
Of course.
It's not my business.
What the? Why is he following me?
Huh?
What's going on?
S***.
Oh. I-I didn't give you back your lighter.
Mr. Lee Kang Hoon.
Oh. Cheol Min!
- You're here early.
- Yeah.
- Have you been well?
- Of course. of course.
But who is this...
I'm a new student here.
Student?
Oh. you're the new transfer kid.
Where's your uniform?
I haven't bought it yet. I'm sorry.
What happened to your arm?
I hurt myself while working.
Drop by the nurse's office first and go to the Architectural Design office.
Okay.
What is he? Was he held back a few years?
Ki Joon. what is your dream?
What the...
I don't know. I forgot.
I have a new dream.
Again?
What is it?
Eun Bi's husband.
Hey. hold on. Where are we going?
What. what?
[Goddess of Nulji. Go Eun Bi's choreography video passes 100k views]
Jong Bok. Is it time yet?
No. not yet.
A firecracker is all about timing.
You know that. right?
Why am I doing this?
You're my friend.
Sure.
She's coming!
[Goddess of Nulji. Go Eun Bi's choreography video passes 100k views]
Who... are you?
What's this? What's going on?
Eun Bi.
What are you doing? Sit down.
The new student should come forward to say hello.
I told you there was a new transfer student coming today. right?
Help him out. okay?
Then. shall we hear him introduce himself?
[11th grade. class 1 Architectural Design Department]
See you later.
Goodbye.
- Finished.
- Aigoo.
What's going on?
Young Joo.
Don't talk to me. you bastard.
I don't want to die.
I tell you. it's him. I saw it with my own eyes.
No way.
When I worked at a factory over the summer. my supervisor was a part of that gang.
That...
The one without a finger...
The new kid's a part of that gang?
What's inside it?
I love you.
I think really big money was being traded.
So all of that is drug dealing?
He doesn't stab people and stuff. does he?
Then...
- was that thing inside the sack...
- I love you.
a corpse?
Hey. Jin Ji Won!
- Hey. hey!
- Oh. no!
- Oh. no.
- Give that to me!
Hello.
What do I do?
You have to watch out for yourself now.
- What do I do?
- Don't say it out loud!
Just stay put.
S***.
Look who it is.
What are you doing here?
Oh.
Long time no see. huh?
What do you mean? I'm asking why you're here.
Oh. well. I...
Mr. Lee Kang Hoon?
Oh. yes.
- Come in.
- Yes.
Mr. Lee?
He'll be replacing Mr. Kim Moo Kyung as the woodworking teacher for the Architectural Design department.
Well. our Mr. Shin Cheol Min recommended you.
so I trust you are a good fit.
Please take good care of our students.
Yes. of course.
He graduated from Jin Sung University
and he worked on-site as a supervisor up until recently.
so he will be a big help to the kids.
Wow. you received a big award in college for woodworking.
You have a lot of on-site experience.
You don't lack anything.
Please help our kids receive a lot of awards.
Of course. I'll do my best.
Class dismissed.
Thank you.
Oh. the new transfer kid. the teaching director was looking for you.
Head down to the office.
Okay.
[2021 Nulji High Woodworking Technique Competition]
[List of awardees / First place: Lee Jae Hee / Second place: Lee Jae Hyeok / Third place: Kang Seo Young]
What's this?
[Second place: Lee Jae Hyeok]
Why am I second place this time?
Be quiet.
Are you happy?
Aren't you embarrassed?
Why are you picking a fight with me again?
Hey. let's go to the snack store!
You look dissatisfied again.
That little...
Hey!
Eun Bi!
You'll hurt your throat. Let's go.
Let's go.
Eun Bi.
Eun Bi. Here's the juice that you like.
Which one do you want?
- This one.
- That's right. Let's go. Eun Bi.
Deep breath in.
Slowly. Good.
Young Joo.
Don't talk to me. you bastard.
I don't want to die.
I have a new dream.
I'll be a professional gamer.
I can't go to the PC room today.
I have to work.
Huh? What work?
Burgerland.
I start today.
Why are you suddenly living so diligently?
When a person suddenly changes...
Well. I guess it doesn't hurt.
Right. Then...
can you...
get me some leftover burgers?
Were you close with him?
Huh?
I'm late. I'm off.
Geez...
[Lion Espresso & Burger]
Geez.
What is it again?
Do you work here?
Yeah. You want a burger?
No.
The new part-timer you told me about.
It was him?
Yeah.
He's handsome.
Whoa.
Why would you look at his looks?
You should judge him by his personality or sense of responsibility.
Oh. so you agree he has good looks?
Anyway. it's a good thing you two are friends.
Teach him properly before you quit next week.
What?
- Me?
- Yeah.
What's your deal these days?
Tell me.
I seriously don't know.
What?
You quit taekwondo. and now you suddenly want to do an apprenticeship.
Is something going on at home?
Just teach me how to work.
What's your deal with the new kid? Why can't you say a thing in front of him?
Hey. Never mind what the deal is with me.
It's unsuitable for us to...
- talk about these things.
- You keep-
What?
You keep hanging around me.
Sorry you keep getting involved with me.
But I have no time to avoid you these days.
I hope you understand.
Come here.
Now.
This is the regular bun.
You use this for cheese and shrimp burgers.
What's this again?
- Re-regular bun.
- Used for what?
- Cheese and shrimp burger.
- Cheese and shrimp burger...
Those. right. Sorry.
It's so frustrating. It's going to take forever.
S***.
Thank you. bye.
Director. can we really order everything we want?
She said she would buy us food if we got all As this semester.
- Right?
- Choose what you want.
Can we get three bacon burgers and three double cheeseburgers?
You should buy healthy food. why would you choose...
Ji Won. why isn't this working?
This keeps happening after the update.
I'll do it.
Fifty-two thousand won. For here?
- Yes.
- Wait...
What's up with her? That Nulji High part-timer.
I know.
Ji Soo. I think we can eat the grape tomatoes right away.
- Really?
- I hope they grow well.
The wind is blowing. the wind is blowing.
Blowing. blowing.
Mom's here!
Jin Ji Won. come downstairs.
We need to talk.
Who are you?
Stop acting like a kid.
I couldn't help it earlier.
What?
I thought you wanted me to act like a stranger.
Dad. say something.
You only make me step in these situations.
You're late.
We were waiting.
How about chicken with beer?
I think the academy director is full.
- Just stop it!
- What? Stop what?
You. The school called again.
You protested with a picket again.
Why would you do that? What's your problem?
You hate that I go to Nulji. not that I protested.
So. did I force you to go to that school?
Why are you so fussy since you were little?
Can't you just be ordinary?
Ordinary how?
I see.
Study ordinarily like everyone else.
just be dumb enough to be average. not even knowing what I love to do.
Go to college because everyone else does and barely graduate
only to be jobless and burden you and Dad? That kind of ordinary?
I won't live like that.
This is so annoying.
That little...
Talking back to me...
Hey. Jin Ji Won!
Was she just talking about me?
Good for you.
At least. you catch on quickly.
That little...
- Come on.
- Excuse me.
Why are you taking it out on a machine?
I'm sorry.
Aren't we in the same class?
Yes.
Don't kick the machine.
Okay.
[Nulji Science and Technology High School]
Well. everyone.
What shall we make today?
To be honest. just knowing how to use the machines is...
You know what I mean. right?
Yes?
We studied using hand tools.
- Why?
- Pardon?
Well. Mr. Kim said we have to know the properties of the wood first...
Oh.
He was that kind of teacher.
Well then. let's see.
Making the roof of a pavilion. Aigoo.
This will take forever.
This isn't so easy.
Then how about...
Oh! Making a pencil holder.
Let's do this.
Excuse me.
Yes?
We did that in 10th grade.
Oh.
You did it?
Okay. good.
This is the basics.
Okay. alright. Then...
Let's see.
But...
why are you looking at me like that?
You have a p-problem with me?
I messed with the wrong kid.
I don't have a problem.
Can you give me back my lighter that you borrowed?
You really-you do whatever you want. huh?
Show some basic manners. at least.
I see.
I don't really know what basic manners are.
This doesn't work well.
The new teacher is interesting.
He's weird.
I liked Mr. Kim better.
You sound pathetic.
Hey. He's much better. He's more qualified.
Oh. I see.
Piss off.
[Lee Kang Hoon]
[Jin Sung University Department of Architecture. Lee Kang Hoon. awarded President's Award for excellence in carpentry]
Gosh. seriously.
Our class atmosphere is so intense.
So scary.
He doesn't seem like a bad kid.
That's not important. Tell us what you were going to say earlier.
Ki Joon followed you to your workplace?
What do you mean followed?
He was just there to work too.
Isn't this pretty much a confession?
- Huh?
- Well. look at it.
He followed you to the apprenticeship. and now he's working where you are.
There are tons of places to work. so why?
I guess that is the only fast food restaurant around here.
Oh. my God.
What are you going to do if Ki Joon confesses to you?
Are you going to accept him?
No way.
He and I are...
arch-nemeses.
Now that you mention it.
what happened to you two in the past?
One person says you guys dated.
another person says you beat each other up.
That little prick played a trick on me. and I hit him.
Hey. Kong Ki Joon!
Really? That's it?
Yeah.
That's all.
All that aside. Gong Ki Joon isn't little anymore.
[Student Records: Jung Young Joo]
[10th and 11th grade: Engineering and Construction / 11th grade: Architectural Design]
Can you give me back my lighter that you borrowed?
Show some basic manners. at least.
This doesn't work well.
Mr. Lee.
You studied architectural design at Jin Sung University. right?
You're fast.
Where did you hear that?
Please establish a carpentry club.
To prepare for this.
[Carpentry competition hosted by Jin Sung University]
I'm going to get in here.
I know external competitions don't count toward the student records.
but I'll go to this university for this major. so I know I'll get bonus points during the interview.
Why do you have to go to this university for this major?
It's the top school I can get in the specialized skill field.
I came to this school so I could get into this college.
As you can see from my last year's transcript.
I never missed the top rank in my studies.
Volunteer work. extracurricular clubs. competitions.
- I prepared the portfolio to fit this major-
- Alright.
What's your name?
Kang Seo Young.
Okay. Seo Young. Let's talk tomorrow.
Good work today.
- Bye.
- See you tomorrow.
[Carpentry competition hosted by Jin Sung University]
What are you going to do if Ki Joon confesses to you?
Are you going to accept him?
All that aside. Gong Ki Joon isn't little anymore.
He use to be a shortie.
Isn't it a rule to spy on someone without them knowing?
What?
You have to fold it properly.
Stupid.
I was doing fine.
I guess it's different.
Hey...
didn't you hurt yourself?
What?
It stings.
Huh?
So suddenly?
Yeah...
Aigoo.
I don't know which of us is stupid here.
You didn't even know you were hurt and kept working?
This is a wound of glory.
What would a newbie like you know?
Wow. is that so?
Why don't you go to a hospital?
You'll get a scar.
It's fine. It's nothing.
Give it to me.
What? Does it remind you of the old days?
What are you talking about?
You kissed me.
Hey.
When? Am I crazy?
That was definitely a mistake. I bumped into you.
Do you like me?
Why are you overreacting?
What are you talking about? Shortie.
I'm not that little kid who cried after you hit me.
Don't make me laugh.
You're still a pathetic little shortie to me.
- Really?
- Really.
♫ Dream on. dream on ♫
♫ Dream on ♫
Then try it again.
♫ My heart keeps thinking of you ♫
♫ I can't even understand myself ♫
♫ I'm always curious about you ♫
♫ I dream of meeting you ♫
♫ Dream on. dream on ♫
♫ Dream on ♫
♫ I'm dreaming right now ♫
♫ Dream on. dream on. dream on ♫
♫ Dream on. I'll grow closer to you ♫
♫ The afternoon sun shimmers on the windowsill ♫
[School 2021]
Didn't you hear what I said?
I told you not to hang around me.
I think Ki Joon's still doing taekwondo.
You won't do it anymore?
Hey. hey!
Say that again. Fun?
Why do you hate Gong Ki Joon?
It's lonely without Ji Won. right?
You should be ready to learn from the ground up.
You're ruining all the future alumni job connections!
- What do you think?
- It's serious.
It's serious.
Why won't you...!
Why won't you pick up the phone?
♫ I can't even understand myself ♫